[
    {
        "question": "1. Who discovered the electron?",
        "options": [
            "J.J. Thomson",
            "Rutherford",
            "Neils Bohr",
            "Chadwick"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Which particle in an atom has a negative charge?",
        "options": [
            "Proton",
            "Neutron",
            "Electron",
            "Nucleus"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is the charge of a neutron?",
        "options": [
            "Positive",
            "Negative",
            "Zero",
            "Variable"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is the center of an atom called?",
        "options": [
            "Electron",
            "Nucleus",
            "Orbit",
            "Neutron"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Who proposed the nuclear model of an atom?",
        "options": [
            "J.J. Thomson",
            "Neils Bohr",
            "Rutherford",
            "Chadwick"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Which subatomic particle was discovered by Chadwick?",
        "options": [
            "Proton",
            "Neutron",
            "Electron",
            "Nucleus"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is the mass of an electron approximately?",
        "options": [
            "1 amu",
            "0.0005 amu",
            "0.5 amu",
            "5 amu"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "8. The maximum number of electrons in the first shell is:",
        "options": [
            "8",
            "2",
            "18",
            "32"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Which of the following is a correct electronic configuration of oxygen (Atomic number 8)?",
        "options": [
            "2,6",
            "6,2",
            "2,8",
            "8,2"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is the name of the model that explains definite energy levels of electrons?",
        "options": [
            "Thomson Model",
            "Rutherford Model",
            "Bohr Model",
            "Quantum Model"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    }
]